monster.ca 2007-12-28

# Monster.ca - Privacy Statement

**  
Monster.ca was recently recognized as having one of the best Privacy Policies in the country!** The report, put out by Nymity Inc., Canada’s leading privacy educator, ranked Monster.ca as one of the top three companies nationwide in our category for privacy protection. [More...](http://about.monster.ca/7210_en-CA_p1.asp)

**Official Privacy Statement    
**  
Monster Canada Worldwide Inc. d/b/a Monster.ca ("Monster.ca") is committed to respecting the privacy of our users. We strive to provide a safe, secure user experience. This Privacy Statement sets forth the online data collection and usage policies and practices that apply to the Monster.ca Web site. By creating an account on the Monster.ca Web site, you consent to the policies and practices described in this Statement. 

Your data will be stored and processed in whole or in part in the United States. If you access the Monster.ca Web site from Canada, your usage of the site constitutes consent to the transfer of your data out of Canada to the United States and acknowledgement that United States governments, courts of law enforcement or regulatory agencies may obtain disclosure of your data through the laws of the United States. 

Our sites contain links to other Web sites over which we have no control. Monster.ca is not responsible for the privacy policies or practices of other Web sites to which you choose to link from the Monster.ca Web site. We encourage you to review the privacy policies of those other Web sites so you can understand how they collect, use and share your information. This Privacy Statement applies solely to the information we collect on the Monster.ca Web site, and does not apply to information we collect in any other fashion. 

**Collection and Retention of Information**

In order to provide you the services of Monster.ca, in some areas of our Web sites, Monster.ca requests or may request that you provide personal information, including your name, address, e-mail address, telephone number credit card number, (if applicable), contact information, billing information and any other information from which your identity is discernible. In order to continually enhance your use of Monster.ca and to provide you requested information about Monster.ca third party partners, in other areas, Monster.ca may collect demographic information that is not unique to you such as your postal code, preferences, interests and favourites. Sometimes we collect or may collect a combination of the two types of information. Examples of areas on the Monster.ca Web site where we collect personal or combined personal and demographic data are pages where you can open a My Monster account, sign up to use a service, post a resume, enter a contest or purchase a product. 

In addition, Monster.ca may indirectly collect information about you when you use certain third party services on our Web site. Such information may be used for the purpose of determining your potential interest in additional services offered by our third party partners. 

We also gather or may gather certain information about your use of our site, such as what areas you visit and what services you access. Moreover, there is information about your computer hardware and software that is or may be collected by Monster.ca. This information can include without limitation your IP address, browser type, domain names, access times and referring Web site addresses. This information is used to evaluate different aspects of the Monster.ca Web Site. The information may also be used for site security and law enforcement purposes. 

Monster.ca may sometimes afford you the opportunity to provide descriptive, cultural, behavioural, preferential and/or life style information about yourself, but it is solely up to you whether you furnish such information. For example, such information may be used for the purpose of determining your potential interest in receiving email or other communications about particular products or services. 

Please remember that if you post any of your personal information in public areas of Monster.ca, such as in online forums or chat rooms, such information may be collected and used by others over whom Monster.ca has no control. We are not responsible for the use made by third parties of information you post or otherwise make available in public areas of Monster.ca. 

Since we believe that managing your career is an on-going process, your job application history is retained by Monster.ca for eighteen (18) months. Of course, you can correct or update your My Monster account profile and resume at any time. Moreover, you can delete your resume from our online database or close your My Monster account at any time, in which event we will remove all our copies of your resume and My Monster account profile information except for an archival copy which is not accessible on the Internet that does not contain any personal identifying information. 

**Use of Information by Monster.ca**

We use the information we gather on the Monster.ca Web site, whether personal, demographic, collective or technical, for the purpose of operating and improving the Monster.ca Web site, fostering a positive user experience, and delivering the products and services that we offer. 

We may also use the information we gather to inform you of other products or services available from Monster.ca or its affiliated companies or to contact you about your opinion of current products and services or potential new products and services that may be offered. (The term "affiliated companies" is defined in the section of this Statement entitled "Contact Information.") 

We may use your contact information in order to send you e-mail or other communications regarding updates at the Monster.ca site, such as new Monster.ca opportunities and additional listings which may be of interest to you. The nature and frequency of these messages will vary depending upon the information we have about you. In addition, at the time of registration for My Monster, you have the option to elect to receive additional communications, information and promotions including without limitation free informational newsletters from Monster.ca relating to topics that may be of special interest to you, such as career management advice. 

We have an area where you can submit feedback. Any feedback you submit in this area becomes our property, and we can use such feedback (such as success stories) for marketing purposes or to contact you for further information. 

**Disclosure of Information to Others**

We do not disclose to third parties your personal information, combined personal and demographic information or information about your use of the Monster.ca Web site (such as the areas you visit or the services you access), except as set forth in the following four subparagraphs. 

  1. We may disclose such information to third parties if you consent to such disclosure. For example, if you indicate that you would like to receive information about the products or services of third parties at the time you register for a My Monster account, we may supply your contact information to third parties such as employers, recruiters, data aggregators, marketers or others for the purpose of sending you e-mail or otherwise communicating with you. We may use data we have about you (such as the interests and preferences you have expressed) to determine whether you might be interested in the products or services of a particular third-party.   

  2. We may disclose such information to companies and individuals we employ to perform functions on our behalf. Examples may include hosting our Web servers, analyzing data, providing marketing assistance, processing credit card payments, and providing customer service. These companies and individuals will have access to your personal information as necessary to perform their functions, but they may not share that information with any other third party.   

  3. We may disclose such information if legally required to do so, if requested to do so by a governmental entity, including a governmental entity of the United States, or if we believe in good faith that such action is necessary to: (a) conform to legal requirements or comply with legal process; (b) protect the rights or property of Monster.ca or its affiliated companies; (c) prevent a crime or protect national security; or (d) protect the personal safety of users or the public.   

  4. We may disclose and transfer such information to a third party who acquires all or a substantial portion of Monster.ca's business, whether such acquisition is by way of merger, consolidation or purchase of all or a substantial portion of our assets. In addition, in the event Monster.ca becomes the subject of a bankruptcy proceeding, whether voluntary or involuntary, Monster.ca or its trustee in bankruptcy may sell, license or otherwise dispose of such information in a transaction approved by the bankruptcy court.  

Monster.ca may also share aggregated anonymous information about visitors to its Web site with its clients, partners and other third parties so that they may understand the kinds of visitors that visit Monster.ca's site and how those visitors use the site. 

Monster.ca and its affiliates supply technology, hosting and related services to other leading companies to power recruitment areas on their Web sites (sometimes referred to as "career site hosting recruitment areas"). Personal and/or demographic information supplied by you in a career site hosting recruitment area becomes part of the Monster.ca database, but it is not accessible by anyone other than you, Monster.ca and the company concerned without your consent. 

Information gathered on a page in a career site hosting recruitment area, or on a co-branded page (such as that of a contest co-sponsored by Monster.ca and another company), may become the property of the other company or of both Monster.ca and the other company. In that instance, the use of such information by the other company may be subject to the privacy policy of that company and, in any event, Monster.ca is not responsible for that company's use of your personal or demographic information. 

**Resumes  
**  
Since Monster.ca is a career site, we give you the option of putting your resume in our database. There are two ways of doing this: 

  1. You can store your resume in our database, but not allow it to be searchable by potential employers. Not allowing your resume to be searchable means that you can use it to apply for a job online, but employers and recruiters will not have access to search it through our resume database product.  

  2. If you allow your resume to be searchable, then all parties with access to our searchable resume database (or copies thereof) will have access to your resume.   

In addition, you can also elect to make your resume confidential which means that your contact info and current employer will be not be displayed to all parties with access to our searchable resume database. 

We attempt to limit access to our searchable resume database (or copies thereof) only to paying employers, recruiters, hiring managers, headhunters, and human resource professionals, as well as law enforcement and national security agencies, but cannot guarantee that other parties will not gain access to this database. We are not responsible for the use made of resumes by third parties who access such resumes while they are in our searchable database. You may remove your resume from our database at any time. However, employers, recruiters and others who have paid for access to that database or to obtain a copy of that database, as well as parties who have otherwise gained access to the database, may have retained a copy of your resume in their own files or databases. We are not responsible for the retention, use or privacy of resumes in these instances. 

**Use of Cookies** Monster.ca uses "cookies" to help personalize and maximize your online experience and time online. A cookie is a text file that is placed on your hard drive by a Web page server. Cookies are not used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer. Cookies are uniquely assigned to your computer, and can only be read by a Web server in the domain that issued the cookie to you. 

One of the primary purposes of cookies is to provide a convenience feature to save you time. The purpose of a cookie is to tell the Web server that you have returned to a specific page. For example, if you personalize Monster.ca pages, or register for services, a cookie helps us to recall your specific information (such as user name, password and preferences). Because of our use of cookies, we can deliver faster and more accurate results and a more personalized site experience. When you return to the Monster.ca site, the information you previously provided can be retrieved, so you can easily use the features that you customized. We also use cookies to track click streams and for load balancing. 

You may have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most Web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline all cookies if you prefer. Alternatively, you may be able to modify your browser setting to notify you each time a cookie is tendered and permit you to accept or decline cookies on an individual basis. If you choose to decline cookies, however, that may hinder performance and negatively impact your experience on the Monster.ca Web site. 

**Use of Web Beacons**

Monster.ca Web pages may contain electronic images known as Web beacons (sometimes called single-pixel gifs) that allow us to count users who have visited those pages and to deliver co-branded services. Web beacons are not used to access your personally identifiable information on Monster.ca; they are a technique we use to compile aggregated statistics about our Web site usage 

Web beacons collect only a limited set of information including a cookie number, time and date of a page view, and a description of the page on which the Web beacon resides. 

**Updating Your Information  
**  
You have the right to demand that your personal information be deleted from Monster.ca. You may review, correct, update or change your My Monster account profile information at any time by simply logging into your My Monster account, going to your [Account Profile](http://my.monster.ca/account/accountedit.aspx), and editing it with the options provided. [Click here](http://my.monster.ca/Login.aspx) to log in to your account. You may review, delete, correct, update or change your resume on Monster.ca at any time by simply logging into your My Monster account, going to Manage resumes, and deleting it or editing it with the options provided. [Click here](http://my.monster.ca/Login.aspx) to log in to your account. You can request that your My Monster account be deleted by [contacting Monster.ca](http://about.monster.ca/9464_en-CA_p1.asp). 

If you opted to receive newsletters, commercial e-mails or other communications from Monster.ca or third parties at the time you registered with My Monster, but subsequently change your mind, you may opt-out by editing your Account Profile as described above. If you previously opted not to receive such communications, you may later opt-in by editing your Account Profile. 

**Security**

Monster.ca has implemented reasonable technical and organizational measures designed to secure your personal information from accidental loss and from unauthorized access, use, alteration or disclosure. However, we cannot guarantee that unauthorized third parties will never be able to defeat those measures or use your personal information for improper purposes. 

When you place an order online at Monster.ca, your credit card information is protected through the use of encryption, such as the Secure Socket Layer ("SSL") protocol. SSL makes it difficult for your credit card information to be intercepted or stolen while being transmitted. Monster.ca uses a service company to process its credit card transactions. For further information on this company's privacy and security practices, please [click here](http://www.verisign.com/truste/index.html). 

**Children**

Monster.ca is not intended for children under 13 years of age. We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under 13. 

**Changes to Privacy Statement  
**  
If we decide to change our Privacy Statement for Monster.ca, we will post those changes here so that you will always know what information we gather, how we might use that information, and to whom we will disclose it. If at any time, you have questions or concerns about Monster.ca's Privacy Statement, please feel free to email us at notification@monster.ca or call us at 1-800-MONSTER and speak to one of our representatives. 

**Contact Information  
**  
Monster.ca is a name under which Monster Canada Worldwide Inc., with its principal place of business at 276 Saint-Jacques Street West, 10th floor, Montreal, Quebec, Canada H2Y 1N3 and certain of its affiliated companies worldwide, do business. ("Affiliated companies" means entities that control, are controlled by or are under common control with Monster Canada Worldwide Inc.). Monster Canada Worldwide Inc. is the legal entity which determines the purposes and means of processing the information gathered at the Monster.ca Web site. The information we gather on the Monster.ca Web site may be shared within Monster Canada Worldwide Inc. and its affiliated companies. 

We welcome your comments concerning this Privacy Statement. If you believe that we have not adhered to this Statement, please contact us by e-mailing us at [notification@monster.ca](mailto:notification@monster.ca?subject=Privacy) or by calling us at 1-800-MONSTER. We will use commercially reasonable efforts to promptly determine and remedy the problem. 

Thank you for using Monster.ca.
